

# JONEL FAELDON

## **SR. FRONTEND ENGINEER**

09171481701

Calamba City, Laguna

 $\smile$ 

jonelfaeldon@gmail.com

in/jonel-faeldon

# **PROFILE**

An object-driven web developer with more than 4 years of experience in frontend and backend development and has successfully delivered over 15 web applications to the clients with quality testing. Those years of developing experience has strengthened my capabilities in interpersonal communication, decision-making and problem solving and is now eager to break into a full-stack developer role.

# **SKILLS**

 Javascript
 HTML
 CSS
 NodeJS
 PHP
 MySQL
 Vue
 React

 CI/CD
 Kubernetes
 Jest
 Github
 Scrum Agile
 Jira
 API Gateways

# **PROJECTS**

### KONSULTAMD EMR

- Developed using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP and MySQL.
- Designed to manage medical records of those subscribed users to the service during online telehealth consultation over the phone and videocalls.
- Built with electronic SMS and email prescriptions beneficial for patients to buy medicine prescribed by the doctors.

### **GISAUTO ADMIN PORTAL**

- Designed to manage a 3 way payload self-service trigger API that can run a web service, a CRON job and download service logs.
- Able to grant dl groups access permission to trigger the service automation, access dashboard and reports and download automation logs.
- Developed using Vue, Vuetify, Vuex, RESTful APIs integrated with Jenkins pipeline for code and image scanning, unit autotesting before deploying the service in production environment.

#### JARVIS HYBRID LIVECHAT

- Set up for all Trend GIS service engineers to manage chat support requests on a 60secs support SLA and create a ticket in Jira.
- Built with react consuming data from AWS services like REDIS, S3 bucket, API gateway and elasticache.

# **EXPERIENCE**

JUN 2021 - PRESENT

#### TREND MICRO, INC

#### SR. FRONTEND ENGINEER

 Focusing on IT services automation, Infrastructure as code, application development and operation with Scrum, CICD, container adoption for agile service delivery and future sustainability with security consideration on public cloud environment (AWS).

AUG 2019 - MAY 2021

#### **EUREKARE CORP.**

#### **BACKEND DEVELOPER**

 Optimized the previous backend services and developed a well structured database, RESTful and SOAP APIs and server setup.

FEB 2018 - JUL 2019

#### **GLOBE TELECOM - KONSULTA MD**

#### WEB DEVELOPER

 Worked with internal cross team members of Konsulta MD service to enhanced the UI/UX of an existing service, integrate legacy systems into web applications and created web applications requested from stakeholders to achieve operation optimization, efficiency and business goal.

MAR 2017 - OCT 2017

### TOOLKIT, INC.

### TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST

 Provided onsite support to the client about the services developed and delivered by our team whether a support to system issue, CRM reports or new feature requests.

NOV 2015 - FEB 2017

#### **CANON BUSINESS MACHINES PHILIPPINES**

### APPLICATION ENGINEER

• Lead integration of company's internal manual process to web application and forms.

# **EDUCATION**

2022-2023 **REFOCUS** 

WEB DEVELOPMENT

2011 - 2015 **POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES** 

**BS. INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY** 

Academic Excellence Awardee